altaro.com 2019-11-04

# Privacy Policy | Altaro

ALTARO LTD (the controller), is a limited liability company organised and existing under the Laws of Malta with registration number C46477 and having a registered office address at: 

'Altaro',  
Block LS3 – Level 1,   
Life Sciences Park,   
San Gwann Industrial Estate,   
San Gwann,   
SGN 3000,   
Malta. 

Altaro are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

### What is personal data and what are special categories of data?

Under the EU's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) personal data is defined as: 

_"any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person”._

The GDPR provides that special categories of data relate to the _"processing of personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, and the processing of genetic data, biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation”_. 

### What personal data do we collect?

Altaro do **_not_** collect any special categories of personal data. 

_Our websites and informational and marketing materials are intended for use by business users_. Business contact information and online usage data is collected through the following channels:

  * Information given directly by you

When ordering or registering on our site or in order to use certain site features, you may be asked to enter your business contact details including your company name and/or website, full name, business e-mail address, corporate postal address and business phone number, in order for us to provide you with the services offered by this site and to enable you to report a problem with the site. Save for such circumstances described, you may visit our site anonymously.

  * Information we obtain from third parties

When ordering our products or services from our business partners, distributors, resellers and/or agents your company name and/or website, full name, business email address, corporate postal address and business phone number will also be provided to us, for us to be able to provide you with the products and services required. 

  * Information we obtain

We also keep track of your corporate IP address and we collect information about your visit, such as how you interact with our site, how long you spend on each page and the page response times, any error information and your clickstream to, through and from our site. For example, we use services to understand how you and other users navigate around the pages on our site. Our analysis is available in aggregate and information collected is not used to target individuals. We will collect information using cookies to monitor usage metrics and we store the cookie data on our partner's platform to allow us to perform our analysis. 

We may also obtain the domain name and operating system of the computer with which you access our site as well as the type of browser you use. This information is automatically processed and obtained through the use of Cookies, and only as necessary in order to enable us to carry out your requests and to be able to provide you with the services you require. 

For more information on what Cookies are, and what they do, please refer to our Cookies Policy. 

### Why do we process the data?

Altaro will process (collect, store and use) the information you provide in a manner compatible with the EU's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This privacy notice tells you how we, Altaro Limited, will collect and use your business contact information and related data. 

The information that you provide to us, we collect from you, or that we collect from other sources is primarily used to provide you with the products and services you are requesting and hence for us to fulfil our obligations and process the sale transaction to which you are party to. 

Moreover, we may collect information from you through the use of Cookies to enable us: 

  * To personalize your experience.  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs). 
  * To improve our website.  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you). 
  * To improve customer service.  
(Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs). 

For more information on what Cookies are, and what they do, please refer to our Cookies Policy. 

We also process the data:

  * To keep you informed of any updates or new products and services we are offering as well as license renewal and related notices; and/or 
  * To inform you of educational and informative resources such as ebooks, webinars and blogs which you may be interested in and/or to send you follow-ups to requested resources such as webinar registration information and recordings. 

In terms of being contacted for marketing and promotional proposes (such as special offers), Altaro requests you to opt-in for such marketing material when you provide your business contact information on the website, unless you are a business partner (agent, reseller, MSP or distributor), in which case it is in our legitimate interest to keep you informed of our products, services, resources and promotions. 

In addition, any email sent informing you of products or services we offer; resources like ebooks, webinars and blogs; or providing other marketing information includes opt-out options enabling you to unsubscribe from such emails. Alternatively, you may unsubscribe by sending an email to [opt-out@altaro.com](mailto:opt-out@altaro.com?subject=Opt-out%20request:%20Please%20unsubscribe%20me). 

We also perform remarketing and retargeting to position targeted ads to appear to you as you browse elsewhere around the Internet after visiting our website. 

In any event, we are committed to ensuring that the information we collect and use is appropriate for this purpose, and does not constitute an invasion of your privacy. 

### Where do we store the data?

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by members of staff operating outside the EEA who work for us. Such members of staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting this data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the General Data Protection Regulation. 

### Will Altaro Limited share the data with anyone else?

We may transfer your data to third-party service providers contracted to Altaro, such as our worldwide partners and affiliates (for example, channel partners, payment processors, data hosts and service providers) in the course of dealing with you. Any third parties that we may share your data with are obliged to keep your details securely, and to use them only to fulfil the service they provide you on our behalf. When they no longer need your data to fulfil this service, they will dispose of the details in line with Altaro's procedures. 

The table below summarizes the type of processing activities performed by third-party service providers with whom we may share your data: 

Looking up corporate website URLs and business contact information such as phone number based on information submitted in the download form on our website or landing pages; and/or verifying status of a potential partner as a VAR or MSP. 

The data is only shared when you sign up for a free software trial or resource and/or have applied to be a partner or MSP and did not purchase the product or service. The extent of data shared is limited to your full name and business email address together with the country of origin. 

We use a service to collect information about your visit, such as how you interact with our site, how long you spend on each page and the page response times, any error information and your clickstream to, through and from our site. 

Data stored is limited to online identifiers (such as anonymous cookie values and IP addresses). 

We use a service to host the data we store in our customer relationship management (CRM) system. 

The data stored on the CRM system is limited to your full name, business email address, business telephone number and corporate address. 

We use marketing automation/email marketing platforms to reach out to our clients via email. 

All data stored within our marketing software solutions are hosted by the solution providers. 

The data stored on the marketing automation/email marketing platforms is limited to your full name, business email address, business telephone number and corporate IP address. 

We use tools to enable our technical support team to chat with potential or existing clients to help with any problems they may face. 

The system enables us to manage cases or queries submitted by potential or existing customers and also hosts our training platform. 

All data inputted in the system is hosted by the system providers. 

The data stored on these systems is limited to your full name, business email address and business telephone number. 

We use a system that allows you to participate in webinars. 

All data submitted is hosted by the software providers. 

The data stored on the system is your full name and business email address. 

Data hosting services 

The data stored is limited to your full name, business email address, corporate address, corporate IP address and business telephone number. 

We provide leads (business contact information including Company name and/or website, your full name, your business email address and business telephone number) to Altaro authorized partners. 

_Any information you choose to post on our blogs or forums or on our social media sites becomes public, which means it could be read, collected and used by others in any manner._ We have no responsibility or liability for any information you choose on submit on these sites. 

### Do we use cookies?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser that enables the sites' or service providers' systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. 

For further, more detailed information on how we use cookies, please refer to our Cookie Policy. 

### Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our websites. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. 

_Any information posted on third-party blogs or forums or on social media sites becomes public, which means it could be read, collected and used by others in any manner._ We have no responsibility or liability for any information you choose on submit on such sites. 

### What steps have Altaro Limited taken to safeguard the data? (Information security)

We work hard to protect Altaro and our users from unauthorised access to or unauthorised alteration, disclosure or destruction of information that we hold. We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your information when you place an order. In particular: 

  * We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers' database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. 
  * We review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorised access to systems.
  * We restrict access to information to Altaro employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it for us and who are subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations. They may be disciplined or their contract terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

We have also taken the necessary steps to ensure that our third-party processors who provide data hosting services or otherwise process data on our behalf, have sufficient safeguards in place to protect your data. In carrying out this assessment, we consider the extent of data transmitted. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

### Under what circumstances will Altaro Limited contact me?

Our aim is not to be intrusive, and we undertake not to ask irrelevant or unnecessary questions. Moreover, the information you provide will be subject to rigorous measures and procedures to minimise the risk of unauthorized access or disclosure. 

### For how long will the data be retained by Altaro Limited?

We will endeavour to keep your information accurate and up to date, and not keep it for longer than is necessary. The data will only be retained for as long as necessary to carry out the processing activity for which the data was collected. In setting the retention period, Altaro also take into consideration their legal obligation to retain information in accordance with the law, such as information needed for audit and taxation purposes. 

### What are your rights as a data subject?

At any point while we are in possession of, or processing thedata, you have the following rights:

  * Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you.
  * Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances, you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
  * Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply, you have a right to restrict the processing.
  * Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation.
  * Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing.
  * Right to object to automated processing, including profiling – you also have the right to be subject to the legal effect of automated processing and profiling.
  * Right to judicial review: in the event that Altaro Limited refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to lodge a complaint to the Supervisory Authority. 

All the above requests may be forwarded, if applicable, to third party processors involved in the processing of the data, as previously listed. 

### Complaints

In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how the data is being processed by Altaro Limited, or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint directly with Altaro Limited by sending an email to [dataprivacy@altaro.com](mailto:dataprivacy@altaro.com). You also have the right to lodge a complaint directly with your local Supervisory Authority. 

### How can you contact us to exercise your rights?

Any questions pertaining to this Privacy Policy or requests to exercise any of your rights, previously mentioned, may be submitted using our contact details listed below: 

Email address: [dataprivacy@altaro.com](mailto:dataprivacy@altaro.com)  
Telephone: +44 (0) 203 397 6280 

Postal Address: 

Altaro Ltd,  
Block LS3 – Level 1, Life Sciences Park,  
San Gwann Industrial Estate,  
San Gwann SGN 3000  
Malta 

We are committed to process your requests within thirty (30) days from receipt, and free of charge. 

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will update the Privacy Policy modification date below and prompt you to read the updated policy when you next visit our website. 

This policy was last modified on **10 July 2019**.

**By using our website, you confirm you have read and accept our privacy policy.**
